Summary
Throughout your radiation treatment,
it is very important to eat well
and maintain the right level of calories.
Ideally,
this means eating without restrictions
as much of the foods you wish to eat
to sustain a healthy body weight.
In this video, we explained common
nutrition challenges during treatment,
introduced you to your nutrition
support team
and explained how we can support you
if you lose weight.
Again, the placement of a feeding tube,
either dobhoff or peg occurs at 10%
loss of body weight.
We want to avoid this for many reasons,
and the best way to do this is to commit
to eating real and complete foods
routinely from the start of treatment.
Nonetheless, despite our best efforts,
there are times when a feeding tube
insertion is the best
and only option for you to be able
to get adequate caloric intake.
If this happens,
we will safely walk you through the steps
of having the feeding
tube placed to best help you.
Thank you for watching.